What the heck are you dressed for?
We're going to dig for sweet potatoes
at the kindergarten today!
What did you see, and where did you see it?!
According to the magazine at
the convenience store,
The Future of Agriculture
According to the magazine at
the convenience store,
everyone working at the farm is dressed like this.
How do you expect to dig potatoes
with a bug catching net?!
Kobato.
Dou sureba iin dakke?
Atarimae no kototte itsumo
Muzukashii na
Ureshii toki waratte
Suki na toki ni utaitai dake
Na no ni
Itsuka negai wa kanau to
Demo "itsuka" tte dore kurai?
Machikirenai yo
123! no aizu de ryoute hirogete
Zenshin ni hikari wo atsumete
Doko ni aru no?
Oshiete, watashi ni dekiru koto
Meippai kizu tsuite
Seiippai hashitte
Nan juu kai koronde naite
Sore de mo mada
Akireru kurai
Ashita wo shinjiteru
...Twilight Search.
Thank you for your help again this year.
Oh it's my pleasure.
Be my guest and take as many as you like.
I can't thank you enough.
Now listen. Whatever potatoes you
dig up, you carry yourself.
Do not dig up more than you can carry.
Now, promise me that.
Kobato, look! They're connected!
Look how big this one is!
You're right! This is like a treasure
hunt, don't you think?
Ouch...
Wow...
That one's huge!
Wow!
D-Dobato...!
Kobato, your bum's all covered in dirt!
Huh?
Who could that be?
He looks a bit older than the
children at Yomogi Kindergarten.
Does he live here, I wonder?
No. The grandchild living here is in high school.
Well then where could he have come from?
Hey you.
Are you alone?
Do you live near here?
Hey wait!
I'm sorry, I should have noticed earlier.
Oh well, some kids tend to be
up to no good, you know.
I wonder if he's from around here.
All right! Time to tidy up. We're leaving!
Okay!
Wow, we sure got a lot!
Kobato!
So many sweet potatoes!
Look at all I got!
Hey.
I thought I told you right at the beginning.
You have to carry the potatoes
you dug up yourself.
Okay, we're having baked sweet
potatoes when we get back.
Yay!
Kobato, are you going to be okay?
Do you want me to help you?
I'm fine! I can carry them all by myself!
That's too many for you to carry. Let me help.
No! It was a promise. We all carry
home what we dug up ourselves!
Of course.
He's so mean.
Th-This is impossible! Give it up, Kobato!
Young lady.
I'll help you!
Really?!
Thank you very much.
Are they ready yet?
It's so smoky!
Wow!
Is it hot?
Here you go!
Thank you!
Be careful, it's hot!
Hey...
Here you are.
Delicious!
So what do we do with all this?
Shall we bake some more?
Why don't we share it with the neighbors?
People of 2-chome
Takahashi
Tsunomoto
Gokura
Shimada
People of 6-chome
Waki
Matsumoto
Ishino
Yoshihata
Fujimoto, will you go with Kobato
and take them to those places?
I'll go alone. It'll be faster.
Hmm... But I'd prefer you both go.
It would be a good opportunity for Kobato
to get to know the neighbors too.
Do you mind, Kobato?
My pleasure!
Kobato is ready!
I won't tell you to help.
Just stay out of my way.
My sweet potatoes!
He's just too mean. All he says to
me is to not get in the way.
But he didn't tell you not to tag along.
But he took the potatoes from me.
I was going to hand them out.
You could also say that he's carrying
them for you because they're heavy.
Yes?
We've come from Yomogi Kindergarten.
We went digging for sweet potatoes and thought
you might like some. They're very good!
Well... Thank you.
We're from Yomogi Kindergarten!
Oh, thank you.
Have some sweet potatoes!
Thank you.
We're from Yomogi Kindergarten!
Fujimoto!
Huh?
We're almost finished handing
out all of the sweet potatoes!
Yeah.
Hey!
Well, well.
You're home.
Good afternoon!
Oh my.
Young lady. How nice to see you.
Yes!
Have you been well, Milk?
You've grown a little, haven't you?
Yes, she has.
She's quite healthy.
It's him.
Oh. He was just passing by.
Asked me if he could use the faucet.
Said he'd been out digging potatoes.
Hey you!
You were at the...
Take this!
Wait!
I told you to wait, didn't I?!
Let go, you thief!
Those are my words, you potato thief!
Let me down!
Fujimoto, what are you doing?!
I'm taking this thief to the police.
No! Please don't! I'll give them back.
I'll give them back, really!
Just as I thought.
You've run away from home.
Run away from home?!
What's your name?
So now you're not talking?
Potato Thief will do.
I'm not a potato thief!
Of course.
You do have a proper name, don't you?
Keita...
Keita? Why did you leave home?
I wanted to go to my old house.
Your old... house?
It's where I used to live. My mom switched
companies, so we had to move.
So how was it? Your old house.
I haven't been there yet.
Are you on your way there now?
I was going to go, but...
You forget where it was, don't you?
I haven't forgotten!
No, the look on your face tells me you forgot.
No!
You wouldn't forget your own house, would you?
Well...
I was only in kindergarten when we moved, so...
Maybe I kind of got lost...
That's called "forgetting".
I haven't forgotten!
Keita.
If you tell us what your house looked like,
we might be able to help you find it.
Can you draw a picture of the house?
Yeah! I can do that!
Um... it was... it had a red roof, and windows
here and here, an antenna, and also...
Draw what was around the house too, okay?
That will make it easier to find.
Oh right. There was a mailbox here.
And a dog lived next door.
That's a big dog.
He always barked when I went by.
Grade 2
Name: Keita Yoshimura
And you know what else?
My mom always baked cookies and stuff.
Wow!
She read me books and took me camping
and to the amusement park on holidays.
Keita?
I want to go back to my old house!
Fujimoto.
I'd like to help Keita find his house.
We've only got a dog and a mailbox to go by.
That's not going to find us his house.
Isn't there anything else you can remember?
Which way? Right? Left?
Um... Th-This way.
No this way?
Oh! I know this place!
I've been here before.
Is that right? We might be close then.
That's wonderful, isn't it Keita?
Yeah.
Did you want to get a drink?
But that's okay. I need to conserve.
Conserve?
You know some difficult words.
My mom always says that.
Over here.
Fujimoto?
Please help yourself.
Why those are...
Pears. Can't you tell?
Here.
Is it okay?
Let's leave some of these in return.
Mmm, this is good!
It is good.
Fujimoto can be a pretty good guy.
Well, I should hope so.
Give me some of that pear, too.
This is great!
Could this dog be?
Which means...
Next door...
This isn't my house.
Yoshimura
We're going in.
Stay back.
My room...
It seems to be locked.
We have no choice but to break it.
No!
Fujimoto!
P-Please...
Please don't break it.
You don't want to go home
to where you live now?
Because Grandpa's there.
Grandpa?
Yeah.
My mom and I, we live at
my grandpa's house now.
Keita, you don't like your grandpa?
He's not nice. He's always mean to me.
Always mean?
Well...
Every morning he nags at me to get up.
Hey! Keita! Get out of bed already!
Hurry up and put that away!
I want to watch more TV at night
and play computer games, too.
Keita!
Grandpa, what did you do that for?!
You shouldn't be up so late. Get to bed!
And at dinner time, he's always
telling me to eat stuff I don't like.
Stuff you don't like?
Like small fish and vegetables...
Keita!
I will not have you wasting food!
Eat what you are served!
Do you think that's being mean?
Sure! Grandpa hates me!
That's why he's always scolding me like that!
He wants me to leave! So I
decided to leave that home!
Keita...
Ms. Sayaka is always telling the
kindergarten students to eat
small fish and vegetables because
they're full of nutrition.
Who's Ms. Sayaka?
Ms. Sayaka is very kind and loves
the children very much.
She's a teacher at Yomogi Kindergarten.
Kind?
Keita!
If you're finished taking
your bath, get to bed!
It's difficult to tell the difference between
someone being mean and not being mean.
But if you look real carefully,
you might be able to tell.
Keita, were you planning on
baking sweet potatoes here?
We baked sweet potatoes together
before and they tasted good.
You take responsibility and take
some of these home with you.
Huh?
I apologized to the lady at the farm for you.
She dug up too many and
this is incredibly heavy.
Isn't that nice, Keita?
Yes.
Can you really get home all by yourself?
Not a problem!
Keita?!
Keita!
Grandpa...
Go on.
Grandpa!
Keita!
Ouch!
Oww! What are you doing, you old fart?
Don't you worry me like that, you silly fool!
Come! We're going home!
Okay.
You're mom's waiting for you at home.
Keita is just about to get on the
train with his grandfather.
Oh not at all. Well then.
Fujimoto, you knew Keita's
home phone number?
Was it you that called Keita's grandfather over?
I don't know. Say, I'm hungry.
Huh?
You want to go home and steam
some sweet potatoes?
Um... Yes.
What is it?
Uh, nothing.
Good evening.
Hi.
Domoto.
On your way home?
I've got stuff to do. I'm going on ahead.
Huh?
Stuff to do?
We went digging for sweet potatoes
with the kindergarten today
and went around handing out
potatoes to the neighbors.
I see.
Fujimoto, he's...
He's actually a nice person isn't he?
Mhm, Fujimoto's a good guy.
Ah, this one's from that rascal.
Keita looked very sad when he
saw the old house though.
I suppose this kompeito is because he
understood how his grandfather truly feels.
I guess so.
Well now for today's score... Seeing that
Fujimoto did much of the work...
You get half, fifty points!
Huh? But Fujimoto was mean
to me this morning.
You're right. Then that offsets the
points and Fujimoto gets a zero.
And you get seventy points
because you tried hard.
Would you mind erasing first before re-writing?
You complain too much. For that,
you're back down to fifty!
Erase it properly, first...
Oh, shut up! Twenty-five points!
What?!
Do you still have a problem? Then 12.5 points!
Oh! My face is all covered in ink now!
Hito wa mina tonde mitai no ni
Juuryoku ni damasareterunda
Dare mo honto wa toberunda yo
Ano ko ga anna ni kanashisou na no wa
Jibun no kage wo
Dokoka ni wasurete kichatta kara kamo
Sore nara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ni ietara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ga waraeba
Ittari kitari ureshiku naru
Kimi ga shiawase ni naru
Shinpai nante iranai yo
Issho ni iru kara
Ureshikuttemo namida ga deru nante
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Hidden Prayer.
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Hidden Prayer.